<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCF on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf/</link><description>Recent content in VCF on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2024, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Native PowerCLI Modules for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-powercli-main/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-powercli-main/</guid><description>
The Birth of PowerVCF Back in January 2020 my friend and colleague Brian OConnell embarked on a community project to write a PowerShell module to make consumption of the VMware Cloud Foundation APIs simple and easy to consume by VI Admins, each cmdlet was hand-built using standard PowerShell verbs that the community is well versed in consuming. He saw that the need for automation within our customer based was growing and at the time there was no alternative solution available.</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Workload Domains</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-04/</guid><description>
This is the final part of my blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. At this point you should have completed the following tasks:
Downloaded All Bundles Initial Health Check SDDC Manager Upgrade SDDC Manager Configuration Drift Update We are now ready to begin the process of upgrading the individual components within a Workload Domain, for this we must first start with the Management Domain before we can carry out any component upgrades of a VI Workload Domain.</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-03/</guid><description>
This is part three of a four part blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. If you have been following the series so far then you will have your bundles downloaded, and performed various health checks to confirm that all is well and will now be ready to start the upgrade process.
Upgrading VMware Cloud Foundation is a multi-stage process, this post will focus on upgrading SDDC Manager which in itself involves two step:</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Perform Health Checks</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-02/</guid><description>
This is part two of a four part blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. In part one we discussed downloading the bundles to SDDC Manager to prepare the system for the upgrade process, in this post we discuss performing the upgrade pre-checks.
Ensuring your VMware Cloud Foundation instance is healthy prior to starting an upgrade is critical to a successful upgrade, SDDC Manager itself has a pre-check process which is executed on a per workload domain basis.</description></item><item><title>Automating the Upgrade of VMware Cloud Foundation with APIs/PowerVCF/PowerShell</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 21-Sep-2023
A couple of years ago I wrote a series of blogs ( see here ) which discussed the process of automating the deployment procedures of VMware Cloud Foundation using the Public APIs, in this new series we will take a look at how we can automate the steps involved in upgrading VMware Cloud Foundation from one release to another.
But before we can begin performing any actual upgrade steps we must carry out some prerequisites which include:</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Download Release Bundles</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-01/</guid><description>
In order to upgrade VMware Cloud Foundation you must first download the upgrade bundles, I recently wrote a blog Automating the Download of VCF Bundles for a Release on this topic which I shared a script vcfBundleDownload.ps1 which can be downloaded from GitHub which we will utilize as part of the procedure here. The script takes a JSON as input where we define the bundle IDs for download but as part of this post I will share a way to automate that part too.</description></item><item><title>Cleaning Up VCF-password* Accounts from vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrslcm-vcf-password/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrslcm-vcf-password/</guid><description>
If you have had VMware Cloud Foundation and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager deployed within your infrastructure for some time you may have noticed in the vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager Password Locker that there are many passwords called VCF-password-&amp;lt; guid &amp;gt;. This is an internal service account used by vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager to make vCenter Server API calls and is rotated automatically by SDDC Manager.
This duplication of accounts happens due to the fact that there is no way to update the existing record and so SDDC Manager has to create a new account when the rotation process occurs.</description></item><item><title>Remove vRealize Log Insight Agent from SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-remove-liagent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-remove-liagent/</guid><description>
If you have ever wanted to remove the vRealize Log Insight from VMware Cloud Foundation you may have skipped the step to uninstall the vRealize Log Insight Linux Agent from SDDC Manager, whilst the process is documented in the VMware documentation for vRealize Log Insight under Uninstall the Log Insight Linux Agent RPM package the procedure does not help you establish the version installed so here is a quick blog to tie all the information together.</description></item><item><title>Introducing a PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-password-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-password-management/</guid><description>
Background In January 2023 through the VMware Validated Solution programme we released both documentation and PowerShell cmdlets to help with the configuration of password policies across the VMware Cloud Foundation platform, enabling our customers to report and configure the password expiration, password complexity, and account lockout policies at scale.
The positive feedback received to date has blown us away and so last month during one of our planning sessions we discussed the merits for spinning out the cmdlets into their own dedicated open-source PowerShell module, during that discussion it was agreed that this would provide us and our customers the following benefits:</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.3.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-230/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-230/</guid><description>
It's been a while since the last update but I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.3.0 for download from the Microsoft PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF v2.3.0 PowerShell Library Download Additions Added region block identifiers for better developer and contributor experience when navigating the PowerShell module code. Added GitHub Pages Documentation for PowerVCF.</description></item><item><title>New Fling - VMware Cloud Foundation Configuration File Generator</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-fling-cfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-fling-cfg/</guid><description>
This week we released a new VMware Fling, VMware Cloud Foundation Configuration File Generator which is a containerized web application developed to replace the Deployment Parameter Workbook used for performing the VMware Cloud Foundation Bring-up of the Management Domain.
VMware Cloud Builder supports providing either the Deployment Parameter Workbook an Excel workbook which is then converted into JSON format and used by the Bring-up engine or simply providing the JSON file already created.</description></item></channel></rss>