<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCF on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf/</link><description>Recent content in VCF on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation and vRealize Suite Flexibility</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrealize-flexibility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrealize-flexibility/</guid><description>
With the release of VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0, VMware removed a number of the vRealize Suite of products from the Bill of Materials (BoM) with the intent of providing customers more flexibility. For more details refer to Flexible vRealize Suite product upgrades of the What's New section of the release notes.
Whilst this is great news for our customers, it has led to a bit of confusion. The release notes simply state:</description></item><item><title>Updating a vSAN License in VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-license-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-license-update/</guid><description>
Ever been in the situation where your licenses assigned in VMware Cloud Foundation are due to expire, well whilst doing some work this week in the lab I noticed that some of mine were coming up for expiration, which got me wondering what the process was to remedy. If you have been in this situation, you probably like me started by checking out the License Management section of the VMware Cloud Foundation Administration Guide and like me ended up being disappointed to find that it only covers the following topics:</description></item><item><title>Fixing Expired Passwords on NSX Manager and Edge Nodes</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-nsxt-passwords/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-nsxt-passwords/</guid><description>
By default NSX-T Data Center passwords (root, admin and audit) on the NSX Manager and NSX Edge nodes are set to expire after 90 days. Unless you rotate passwords on regular basis you may have overlooked this default configuration and suddenly find yourself locked out of being able to perform management tasks.
Firstly in more recent releases, VMware Cloud Foundation provides the ability to perform scheduled or manual password rotations something to consider looking into from a day-to-day operational process but if your passwords have already expired all bets are off as the VMware Cloud Foundation password rotation workflow can no longer authenticate.</description></item><item><title>Automating the Download of VCF Bundles for a Release</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</guid><description>
If you have been through the process of performing an upgrade of VMware Cloud Foundation you will know the process involves downloading a number of bundles. VMware Cloud Foundation includes the following types of bundles.
Install Bundles, An install bundle includes software binaries to install VI workload domains and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager. Update or Upgrade Bundle, An update or upgrade bundle includes software binaries to update the appropriate VMware Cloud Foundation software components.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</guid><description>
It's been a while since the last update but I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.2.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF v2.2.0 PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed Get-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet when passing the ID of the Application Virtual Network the response was failing. Enhancements Updated Get-VCFFederation cmdlet to check the system version, multi-instance management is deprecated in VMware Cloud Foundation v4.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Enhancements Renamed Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet. Renamed Set-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvROPs to align with new Get-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.3 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.3 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Enhancements Updated ResponseException cmdlet to improve the error handling message output. Additions Added Add-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet to create the Application Virtual Networks. If you would like to learn more about VMware Cloud Foundation or PowerVCF, check out these links:</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Builder - Bringup Validation for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-validation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-validation/</guid><description>
Background For those of you who are not familiar with VMware Cloud Builder its a virtual appliance that is shipped as part of VMware Cloud Foundation. It's primary goal is to bootstrap the deployment and configuration of the Management Domain which includes ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager.
VMware Cloud Builder was first released to support the automated deployment of the VMware Validated Design 5.0 and as part of that development work the team started with a virtual appliance known as Cloud VM which was used by Service Providers to deploy a different version of VMware Cloud Foundation back in the 2.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.2 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.2 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
This latest release is a very minor update containing a few bug fixes as well as adding support for the new VIEWER Role added in VMware Cloud Foundation 4.2 within the New-VCFGroup cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Builder Validation: SSL Certificate common name doesn’t match ESXi FQDN</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-esxi-certs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-esxi-certs/</guid><description>
On February 9th VMware released VMware Cloud Foundation 4.2, and with it a number of new security enhancements, one of which means that each ESXi host used for either a Management Domain or Workload Domain now requires the self-signed certificate for the ESXi host to have its common name matching the real FQDN assigned to the host.
Failure to follow the procedure will result in the validation task failing with the error message: 'SSL Certificate common name doesn’t match ESXi FQDN'.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.1 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.1 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.
Categorycmdlet NameDescriptionCommentUsers and GroupsGet-VCFCredentialRetrieves a list of credentials.UPDATE: Added support for the vRealize credentialsBundlesStart-VCFBundleUploadStarts upload of bundle to SDDC ManagerUPDATE: Allows the import of a bundle based on offline download.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.1.0 Here's a run down of what's new in this release:
Rename of a few existing cmdlets to align with approved verbsEnhancements to execution response messagesRemoval of the use of Write-Host The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.0.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.0.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.0&amp;lt; Along with a number of new or modified cmdlets the following enhancements have been made:
Grouped cmdlets based on order of API documentationEnhancements to reuse duplicate codeUpdated for consistency in the use of codeSupport for the new token-based authentication model The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v1.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</guid><description>
If you follow my posts you will know that in January I posted about the release of PowerVCF which is a PowerShell based CLI that exposes the public APIs of VMware Cloud Foundation to be easily consumed by VI Admins (see Introducing PowerVCF – Power to VI Admins).
As mentioned before PowerVCF is a open source project and the team has been working hard in their spare time to continue to evolve the cmdlets it offers.</description></item><item><title>Introducing PowerVCF - Power to VI Admins</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</guid><description>
Back in December I was chatting with my good friend and colleague Brian O'Connell about automating a bunch of post configuration tasks within VMware Cloud Foundation using the new Public APIs, and it was during that conversation he shared a pet project he had been working on called PowerVCF, the idea behind PowerVCF being a way to allow VI Admin's to easily consume the new public APIs we began shipping with VMware Cloud Foundation much in the same way PowerNSX and PowerVRA come about.</description></item></channel></rss>