<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCF PowerCLI on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf-powercli/</link><description>Recent content in VCF PowerCLI on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2025, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf-powercli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Srm: Commands for VMware Live Site Recovery in PowerCLI</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-srm-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-srm-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Srm, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support VMware Live Site Recovery Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Display All VMware Live Recovery GET Command Details Start a PowerShell session.
Display all GET cmdlets supported in VMware.Sdk.Srm by running the following command:
1Get-SrmOperation -Method Get | Select-Object CommandInfo, Path, Method Output for all GET cmdlets in VMware.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vsphere: Commands for vSphere</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vsphere-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vsphere-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vsphere, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support vSphere Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a vCenter Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a vCenter instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VIServer -Server sfo-m01-vc01.sfo.rainpole.io -Username administrator@vsphere.local -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $global:DefaultVIServer. 1Name : sfo-m01-vc01.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vcf.SddcManager: Commands for SDDC Manager in PowerCLI</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sddcm-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sddcm-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vcf.SddcManager, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support SDDC Manager Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a SDDC Manager Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a SDDC Manager instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VcfSddcManagerServer -Server sfo-vcf01.sfo.rainpole.io -User administrator@vsphere.local -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultSddcManagerConnections.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Nsx.Policy: Commands for NSX</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-nsx-policy-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-nsx-policy-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Nsx.Policy, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support NSX Policy Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a NSX Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a NSX instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-NsxServer -Server sfo-m01-nsx01.sfo.rainpole.io -User admin -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultNsxConnections.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Installer: Commands for VCF Installer in PowerCLI</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vcfinstaller-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vcfinstaller-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Installer, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support VCF Installer Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a VCF Installer Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a VCF Installer instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VcfInstallerServer -Server sfo-ins01.sfo.rainpole.io -User admin@local -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultInstallerConnections.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Ops: Commands for VCF Operations</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-operations-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-operations-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Ops, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support VCF Operations Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a VCF Operations Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a VCF Operations instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VcfOpsServer -Server flt-ops01a.rainpole.io -User admin -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultOpsConnections.</description></item><item><title>VCF PowerCLI 9.0: Understanding PowerCLI SDK Cmdlets</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sdk-modules/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sdk-modules/</guid><description>
Along with the release of VMware Cloud Foundation 9.0 a new version of PowerCLI has also been shipped, for a full rundown of what's new I would suggest reading the official blog Introducing VCF PowerCLI 9.0 , but here are the quick highlights:
Name Change to VCF PowerCLI Performance Improvements New Module for NSX Virtual Private Cloud New Module for SDDC Manager Usability improvements with PowerCLI SDK Global Authorization APIs and PowerCLI bindings Bug fixes For the purposes of this blog I want to focus on the PowerCLI SDK improvements.</description></item><item><title>How to Install VCF PowerCLI 9.0: Step-by-Step Guide</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-updating/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-updating/</guid><description>
The fastest and easiest way to start utilising VCF PowerCLI 9.0 is to first remove any old versions and then perform a fresh install.
Remove Existing VMware PowerCLI Modules Start a PowerShell session.
Uninstall all VMware modules by running the following command:
1Get-Module VMware* -ListAvailable | Uninstall-Module -Force -AllVersions Verify that all VMware modules have been uninstalled by running the following command: 1Get-Module VMware* -ListAvailable Installing VCF PowerCLI 9.0 Start a PowerShell session.</description></item></channel></rss>