<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Operations Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide operations monitoring, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Operations and the configuration of it's management packs to collect data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.
The roles and personas documented (here) should be considered as a minimum requirement when implementing the Intelligent Operations Management validated solution but there is nothing stopping customers adding more granular roles where possible or even personas that better align with their own organizations roles and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Logging and Analytics Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide logging, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Log Insight and the configuration of it's content packs to collect log data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Developer Ready Infrastructure Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide enterprise grade infrastructure, suitable for developers to consume for the deployment of modern applications, using VMware Cloud Foundation as its foundational layer.
The Developer Ready Infrastructure validated solution achieves this by walking you through the configuration of each of the required components including NSX-T Data Center, vSphere Storage Policies, vSphere Tanzu and more.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #9 (Sep 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-09/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 27-Sep-2022
Welcome to Edition #9 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Added automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.8.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.8.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Delighted to announce the release of a this brand new VMware Validated Solution.</description></item><item><title>Terraform - Learning Some Basics</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/terraform/terraform-intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/terraform/terraform-intro/</guid><description>
During the last couple of months I've been working on a new project which has given me the opportunity to delve back into Terraform. I first took a look at Terraform in late 2020 while doing some research around automating VMware Validated Solutions, at the time there were far too many gaps in the providers which made it difficult to justify its use to deliver end to end automation with very short time scales.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation and vRealize Suite Flexibility</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrealize-flexibility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrealize-flexibility/</guid><description>
With the release of VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0, VMware removed a number of the vRealize Suite of products from the Bill of Materials (BoM) with the intent of providing customers more flexibility. For more details refer to Flexible vRealize Suite product upgrades of the What's New section of the release notes.
Whilst this is great news for our customers, it has led to a bit of confusion. The release notes simply state:</description></item><item><title>Updating a vSAN License in VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-license-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-license-update/</guid><description>
Ever been in the situation where your licenses assigned in VMware Cloud Foundation are due to expire, well whilst doing some work this week in the lab I noticed that some of mine were coming up for expiration, which got me wondering what the process was to remedy. If you have been in this situation, you probably like me started by checking out the License Management section of the VMware Cloud Foundation Administration Guide and like me ended up being disappointed to find that it only covers the following topics:</description></item><item><title>Fixing Expired Passwords on NSX Manager and Edge Nodes</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-nsxt-passwords/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-nsxt-passwords/</guid><description>
By default NSX-T Data Center passwords (root, admin and audit) on the NSX Manager and NSX Edge nodes are set to expire after 90 days. Unless you rotate passwords on regular basis you may have overlooked this default configuration and suddenly find yourself locked out of being able to perform management tasks.
Firstly in more recent releases, VMware Cloud Foundation provides the ability to perform scheduled or manual password rotations something to consider looking into from a day-to-day operational process but if your passwords have already expired all bets are off as the VMware Cloud Foundation password rotation workflow can no longer authenticate.</description></item><item><title>Automating the Download of VCF Bundles for a Release</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</guid><description>
If you have been through the process of performing an upgrade of VMware Cloud Foundation you will know the process involves downloading a number of bundles. VMware Cloud Foundation includes the following types of bundles.
Install Bundles, An install bundle includes software binaries to install VI workload domains and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager. Update or Upgrade Bundle, An update or upgrade bundle includes software binaries to update the appropriate VMware Cloud Foundation software components.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Blog Index</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated 31-05-2022 VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. Over time the team intends to add incremental value where opportunities arise and I plan to share as much detail as I can with each new update using my What's New for VMware Validated Solutions series of blog posts. I've decided to create this single landing page where I will provide a consolidated list of links to the relevant Editions of this series so you can bookmark this single page for ease of use.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #8 (May 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 31-May-2022
Welcome to Edition #8 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Added automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</guid><description>
It's been a while since the last update but I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.2.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF v2.2.0 PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed Get-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet when passing the ID of the Application Virtual Network the response was failing. Enhancements Updated Get-VCFFederation cmdlet to check the system version, multi-instance management is deprecated in VMware Cloud Foundation v4.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #7 (Apr 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Apr-2022
Welcome to Edition #7 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation
Add a VMware Identity Manager Adapter for the Standalone Workspace ONE Access Instance (Add-vROPSAdapterIdentityManager) Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Solution Interoperability Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #6 (Mar 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 29-Mar-2022
Welcome to Edition #6 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.5.0 release Additional Operational Guidance (example Personas) Additional automation for procedures within Solution Interoperability section Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Design Decision Changes
IAM-WSA-LOG-003 - Configure a dedicated Workspace ONE Access agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN (NEW) IAM-WSA-LOG-004 - Configure a dedicated Photon OS agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #5 (Feb 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 22-Feb-2022
Welcome to Edition #5 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.4.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Advanced Load Balancer for VMware Cloud Foundation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Added a procedure for configuring a Ping adapter for the standalone Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #4 (Jan 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Jan-2022
Welcome to Edition #4 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.3.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support for the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.
Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Added PowerValidatedSolutions automation to the following procedures:</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Identity and Access Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution it’s primary purpose is to provide customers a consistent way of integrating the foundational components of VMware Cloud Foundation (vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager) with an organizations identify provider delivering operational consistency and flexibility.
The Identity and Access Management solution achieves this by connecting components using Active Directory over LDAP/LDAPS and utilizing Active Directory Global Groups to assign individual component level role access and then nested Global Groups to assign a collection of roles based on personas.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</guid><description>
Are you using the PowerValidatedSolutions PowerShell module? Have you found an issue that you want to report? Maybe you have an enhancement idea!
The source code for PowerValidatedSolutions can be found on Git Hub at https://github.com/vmware-samples/power-validated-solutions-for-cloud-foundation, from here you can log issues and enhancements. Fork the branch and provide direct contributions.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</guid><description>
Did you know that the PowerShell module PowerValidatedSolution can be used for more than implementing the VMware Validated Solutions?
Whilst the primary goal for the PowerShell module has been to enable a robust and automated way to implement the various procedures across solutions, its very nature unlocks the power for cmdlet's to be used across the VMware portfolio. One of the fundamental directives for our development work was to minimize the reliance on other PowerShell modules.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Enhancements Renamed Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet. Renamed Set-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvROPs to align with new Get-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #3 (Nov 2021)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 30-Nov-2021
Welcome to Edition #3 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
General Availability of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0 Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0, which is a PowerShell module that we have developed to not only accelerate the implementation of Validated Solutions, but ensure consistency and robustness. Here's a list of what's changed (this and previous updates can be tracked by reading the CHANGELOG.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution places certain configuration requirements on VMware Cloud Foundation, this detailed is documented within the Before You Apply This Guidance section of the Solution Guide.
To locate the Before You Apply This Guidance use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Click on the top page of the docs.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item><item><title>VMware Validated Solutions - Tips Index</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 10-Nov-2021
VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. To help customers get the most out of VMware Validated Solutions I've put together a number of short tips, bookmark this page for easy access.
Remember to check back from time to time!
Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution is validated against a specific architecture configuration of VMware Cloud Foundation, to confirm and identify if your configuration is supported you use the Design Objectives table.
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Review the VMware Cloud Foundation architecture support and Workload domain type support rows to confirm support.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</guid><description>
When updates are made to VMware Validated Solutions the changes could affect a section of the guide or the whole guide, each page within the guide itself has an Updated on value at the top of the page.
In addition its possible to identify where content has changed from individual Validated Solution resource page on core.vmware.com, each tile which provides a link to a particular section of the content has a date too, this is updated each time changes are made within that section.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</guid><description>
As each VMware Validated Solution is updated its important that you as the customer are able to obtain a precise and accurate account of what has changed within the guide, Validated Solutions do this through the use of an Update History table that is published within the About section of the document.
To locate the Update History use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</guid><description>
VMware Validated Solutions have been developed so that they can support multiple versions of VMware Cloud Foundation, this means they only need to be updated when absolutely necessary which is typically driven by significant architecture changes.
There are two methods that you can use to identify if a particular solution is supported for the VMware Cloud Foundation release you have deployed.
Method One - Viewing Tags on core.vmware.com VMware utilizes a single landing page within the Cloud Platform Tech Zone website known as core.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #2 (Oct 2021)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 26-Oct-2021
Welcome to Edition #2 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing a number of incremental changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.1.0 release Additional Operational Guidance Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support of the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #1</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 05-Oct-2021
Last month we released VMware Validated Solutions for background reading check out my original post here, this fundamental shift in developing VMware Validated Solutions now allows us to deliver incremental value over time, this is just the first of what I hope to be many updates but I'm really excited to share the following announcements with you all today:
General Availability of Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation The Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution, illustrates adapting a dual-instance software-defined data center (SDDC), deployed on top of VMware Cloud Foundation, to provide disaster recovery of the vRealize Automation and vRealize Operations Manager components within the Management Domain as well as lay the foundation to protected customer workloads within the VI Workload Domain.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.3 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.3 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Enhancements Updated ResponseException cmdlet to improve the error handling message output. Additions Added Add-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet to create the Application Virtual Networks. If you would like to learn more about VMware Cloud Foundation or PowerVCF, check out these links:</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Builder - Bringup Validation for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-validation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-validation/</guid><description>
Background For those of you who are not familiar with VMware Cloud Builder its a virtual appliance that is shipped as part of VMware Cloud Foundation. It's primary goal is to bootstrap the deployment and configuration of the Management Domain which includes ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager.
VMware Cloud Builder was first released to support the automated deployment of the VMware Validated Design 5.0 and as part of that development work the team started with a virtual appliance known as Cloud VM which was used by Service Providers to deploy a different version of VMware Cloud Foundation back in the 2.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.2 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.2 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
This latest release is a very minor update containing a few bug fixes as well as adding support for the new VIEWER Role added in VMware Cloud Foundation 4.2 within the New-VCFGroup cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Builder Validation: SSL Certificate common name doesn’t match ESXi FQDN</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-esxi-certs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-esxi-certs/</guid><description>
On February 9th VMware released VMware Cloud Foundation 4.2, and with it a number of new security enhancements, one of which means that each ESXi host used for either a Management Domain or Workload Domain now requires the self-signed certificate for the ESXi host to have its common name matching the real FQDN assigned to the host.
Failure to follow the procedure will result in the validation task failing with the error message: 'SSL Certificate common name doesn’t match ESXi FQDN'.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.1 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.1 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.
Categorycmdlet NameDescriptionCommentUsers and GroupsGet-VCFCredentialRetrieves a list of credentials.UPDATE: Added support for the vRealize credentialsBundlesStart-VCFBundleUploadStarts upload of bundle to SDDC ManagerUPDATE: Allows the import of a bundle based on offline download.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.1.0 Here's a run down of what's new in this release:
Rename of a few existing cmdlets to align with approved verbsEnhancements to execution response messagesRemoval of the use of Write-Host The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.0.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.0.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.0&amp;lt; Along with a number of new or modified cmdlets the following enhancements have been made:
Grouped cmdlets based on order of API documentationEnhancements to reuse duplicate codeUpdated for consistency in the use of codeSupport for the new token-based authentication model The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v1.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</guid><description>
If you follow my posts you will know that in January I posted about the release of PowerVCF which is a PowerShell based CLI that exposes the public APIs of VMware Cloud Foundation to be easily consumed by VI Admins (see Introducing PowerVCF – Power to VI Admins).
As mentioned before PowerVCF is a open source project and the team has been working hard in their spare time to continue to evolve the cmdlets it offers.</description></item><item><title>Introducing PowerVCF - Power to VI Admins</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</guid><description>
Back in December I was chatting with my good friend and colleague Brian O'Connell about automating a bunch of post configuration tasks within VMware Cloud Foundation using the new Public APIs, and it was during that conversation he shared a pet project he had been working on called PowerVCF, the idea behind PowerVCF being a way to allow VI Admin's to easily consume the new public APIs we began shipping with VMware Cloud Foundation much in the same way PowerNSX and PowerVRA come about.</description></item></channel></rss>