<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Public APIs on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/public-apis/</link><description>Recent content in Public APIs on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2025, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/public-apis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Authentication Using Curl for VCF Operations Fleet Management</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/ops-fleet-mgmt/ofm-curl-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/ops-fleet-mgmt/ofm-curl-authentication/</guid><description>
In this post we will look at the process of authenticating to VCF Operations Fleet Management.
VCF Operations Fleet Management APIs Used
GET /lcmversion Authenticating to VCF Operations Fleet Management Using Curl Procedure
Connect to a Linux based operating system over SSH. Replace the values in the sample code with values for your VCF Operations Fleet Management and run the commands SSH session. 1ariaSuiteLifecycleFqdn=$&amp;#39;flt-fm01.rainpole.io&amp;#39; 2ariaSuiteLifecycleUser=$&amp;#39;admin@local&amp;#39; 3ariaSuiteLifecyclePass=$&amp;#39;VMw@re1!VMw@re1!&amp;#39; Connect to VCF Operations Fleet Management with the provided credentials and check the health by running the following command: 1curl -k -X GET &amp;#34;https://$ariaSuiteLifecycleFqdn/lcm/health/api/v2/status&amp;#34; -u &amp;#34;$ariaSuiteLifecycleUser:$ariaSuiteLifecyclePass&amp;#34; -H &amp;#34;accept: application/json&amp;#34; -H &amp;#34;Content-Type: application/json&amp;#34; | json_pp</description></item><item><title>Obtaining a Token Using Curl for VCF Operations for Networks</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/ops-for-networks/ofn-curl-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/ops-for-networks/ofn-curl-authentication/</guid><description>
In this post we will look at the process of obtaining an authentication token from VCF Operations for networks which we can then use in subsequent API requests.
VCF Operations for Networks APIs Used
POST /api/ni/auth/token DELETE /api/ni/auth/token GET /api/ni/info/version Obtaining an Authentication Token From VCF Operations for Networks In this procedure, we will use the /api/ni/auth/token API passing valid credentials to perform the authentication process and obtain an authentication token for the session.</description></item><item><title>Viewing Service Details Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-view-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-view-services/</guid><description>
In this procedure, we will use the /v1/vcf-services API to retrieve service details for a SDDC Manager instance.
SDDC Manager APIs Used
POST /v1/tokens GET /v1/vcf-services Obtaining Service Details for all Services from SDDC Manager Procedure
Connect to the SDDC Manager appliance over SSH. Replace the values in the sample code with values for your SDDC Manager instance and run the commands SSH session. 1sddcManagerFqdn=$&amp;#39;sfo-vcf01.sfo.rainpole.io&amp;#39; 2sddcManagerUser=$&amp;#39;admin@local&amp;#39; 3sddcManagerPass=$&amp;#39;VMw@re1!VMw@re1!&amp;#39; Authenticate to SDDC Manager and obtain a token by running the following command: 1TOKEN=$(curl -k -X POST https://$sddcManagerFqdn/v1/tokens -H &amp;#39;Content-Type:application/json&amp;#39; -d &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#39;$sddcManagerUser&amp;#39;&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#39;$sddcManagerPass&amp;#39;&amp;#34;}&amp;#39; | jq -r &amp;#39;.</description></item><item><title>Viewing Network Pool Details Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-view-network-pools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-view-network-pools/</guid><description>
In this post we will use curl to view the details of a Network Pool in SDDC Manager.
SDDC Manager APIs Used
POST /v1/tokens GET /v1/network-pools View All Network Pools Configured in SDDC Manager In this procedure we will authenticate to SDDC Manager and then using the /v1/network-pools API we will retrieve a list of all the Network Pools configured within the SDDC Manager instance.
Procedure
Connect to the SDDC Manager appliance over SSH.</description></item><item><title>Obtaining a Token Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-authentication/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-authentication/</guid><description>
Interacting with the Public APIs for SDDC Manager can be achieved in many ways, my normal goto is PowerCLI but that requires the installation of the required modules and of course PowerShell itself to be available on either the component your wanting to interact with or a remote management host. If your looking for a faster method for interacting with the Public APIs then CURL is your new best friend.</description></item></channel></rss>