<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VVS on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vvs/</link><description>Recent content in VVS on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vvs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Password Policies for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-confg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-confg/</guid><description>
In a recent blog (see here) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Start-PasswordPolicyConfig which actually performs the configuration of all password policies across the VMware Cloud Foundation instance.
The Start-PasswordPolicyConfig cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Validated Solutions and provides the ability to automate the configuration of password policies using the provided configuration JSON for the following components:</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #14 (Mar 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-14/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Mar-2023
Welcome to Edition #14 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation New Solution - Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.1.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Delighted to announce the release of two brand new VMware Validated Solutions this month.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #13 (Feb 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-13/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Feb-2023
Welcome to Edition #13 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added enhancements to Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Added enhancements to Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Detailed Design
Updates to the following design decisions:
Design Decisions on Identity Management
CBO-IAM-SEC-003 - Assign vRealize Operations Cloud service roles to designated users.</description></item><item><title>Generating Password Policy Reports for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</guid><description>
In a recent blog (see here) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager to generate the password policy reports.
The Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Validated Solutions and provides the ability to generate two types of HTML reports:
An HTML report showing the current configuration for password expiration, password complexity and account lockout for each component.</description></item><item><title>Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation Overview</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</guid><description>
Password Policy Configuration may not be that important to some but for security teams it’s critical for ensuring their organization is protected. If you have ever looked deep into this area when it comes to VMware Cloud Foundation and the components involved you will quickly realize that unfortunately VMware today does not make things easy for our customers. We have:
lack of consistency with default values lack of consistency with common parameters lack of consistency with API methods lack of consistency with terminology and language This is why with the January Update to VMware Validated Solutions (see here) we have spent a significant amount of time reviewing and rewriting all aspects of our content as it relates to Password Policy Configuration.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #12 (Jan 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-12/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 31-Jan-2023
Welcome to Edition #12 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Enhancements to Password Policy Configuration within Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.0.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Delighted to announce the release of this brand new VMware Validated Solution.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #11 (Nov 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-11/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 29-Nov-2022
Welcome to Edition #11 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added improvements to the implementation prerequisites across all VMware Validated Solutions Added improvements to PowerShell functions for Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Added certificate replacement procedures for Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.10.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Implementation Prerequisites Improvements Following feedback we have incorporated improvements to the implementation prerequisites section of each solution guide.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #10 (Oct 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-10/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Oct-2022
Welcome to Edition #10 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.5.0 Added automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.9.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.9.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.5.0 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.5.0.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Additional automation provided by PowerValidatedSolutions:</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Private Cloud Automation Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-pca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-pca/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to implement a modern cloud automation platform that delivers self-service automation, DevOps for infrastructure, and orchestration.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Automation and the integration with one of more VMware Cloud Foundation instances.
The roles and personas documented (here) should be considered as a minimum requirement when implementing the Private Cloud Automation validated solution but there is nothing stopping customers adding more granular roles where possible or even personas that better align with their own organizations roles and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Operations Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide operations monitoring, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Operations and the configuration of it's management packs to collect data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.
The roles and personas documented (here) should be considered as a minimum requirement when implementing the Intelligent Operations Management validated solution but there is nothing stopping customers adding more granular roles where possible or even personas that better align with their own organizations roles and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Logging and Analytics Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide logging, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Log Insight and the configuration of it's content packs to collect log data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Developer Ready Infrastructure Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide enterprise grade infrastructure, suitable for developers to consume for the deployment of modern applications, using VMware Cloud Foundation as its foundational layer.
The Developer Ready Infrastructure validated solution achieves this by walking you through the configuration of each of the required components including NSX-T Data Center, vSphere Storage Policies, vSphere Tanzu and more.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #9 (Sep 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-09/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 27-Sep-2022
Welcome to Edition #9 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Added automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.8.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.8.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Delighted to announce the release of a this brand new VMware Validated Solution.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Blog Index</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated 28-Feb-2023 VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. Over time the team intends to add incremental value where opportunities arise and I plan to share as much detail as I can with each new update using my What's New for VMware Validated Solutions series of blog posts. I've decided to create this single landing page where I will provide a consolidated list of links to the relevant Editions of this series so you can bookmark this single page for ease of use.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #8 (May 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 31-May-2022
Welcome to Edition #8 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Added automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #7 (Apr 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Apr-2022
Welcome to Edition #7 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation
Add a VMware Identity Manager Adapter for the Standalone Workspace ONE Access Instance (Add-vROPSAdapterIdentityManager) Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Solution Interoperability Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #6 (Mar 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 29-Mar-2022
Welcome to Edition #6 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.5.0 release Additional Operational Guidance (example Personas) Additional automation for procedures within Solution Interoperability section Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Design Decision Changes
IAM-WSA-LOG-003 - Configure a dedicated Workspace ONE Access agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN (NEW) IAM-WSA-LOG-004 - Configure a dedicated Photon OS agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #5 (Feb 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 22-Feb-2022
Welcome to Edition #5 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.4.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Advanced Load Balancer for VMware Cloud Foundation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Added a procedure for configuring a Ping adapter for the standalone Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #4 (Jan 2022)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Jan-2022
Welcome to Edition #4 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.3.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support for the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.
Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Added PowerValidatedSolutions automation to the following procedures:</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Identity and Access Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution it’s primary purpose is to provide customers a consistent way of integrating the foundational components of VMware Cloud Foundation (vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager) with an organizations identify provider delivering operational consistency and flexibility.
The Identity and Access Management solution achieves this by connecting components using Active Directory over LDAP/LDAPS and utilizing Active Directory Global Groups to assign individual component level role access and then nested Global Groups to assign a collection of roles based on personas.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #3 (Nov 2021)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 30-Nov-2021
Welcome to Edition #3 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
General Availability of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0 Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0, which is a PowerShell module that we have developed to not only accelerate the implementation of Validated Solutions, but ensure consistency and robustness. Here's a list of what's changed (this and previous updates can be tracked by reading the CHANGELOG.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution places certain configuration requirements on VMware Cloud Foundation, this detailed is documented within the Before You Apply This Guidance section of the Solution Guide.
To locate the Before You Apply This Guidance use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Click on the top page of the docs.</description></item><item><title>VMware Validated Solutions - Tips Index</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 10-Nov-2021
VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. To help customers get the most out of VMware Validated Solutions I've put together a number of short tips, bookmark this page for easy access.
Remember to check back from time to time!
Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution is validated against a specific architecture configuration of VMware Cloud Foundation, to confirm and identify if your configuration is supported you use the Design Objectives table.
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Review the VMware Cloud Foundation architecture support and Workload domain type support rows to confirm support.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</guid><description>
When updates are made to VMware Validated Solutions the changes could affect a section of the guide or the whole guide, each page within the guide itself has an Updated on value at the top of the page.
In addition its possible to identify where content has changed from individual Validated Solution resource page on core.vmware.com, each tile which provides a link to a particular section of the content has a date too, this is updated each time changes are made within that section.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</guid><description>
As each VMware Validated Solution is updated its important that you as the customer are able to obtain a precise and accurate account of what has changed within the guide, Validated Solutions do this through the use of an Update History table that is published within the About section of the document.
To locate the Update History use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</guid><description>
VMware Validated Solutions have been developed so that they can support multiple versions of VMware Cloud Foundation, this means they only need to be updated when absolutely necessary which is typically driven by significant architecture changes.
There are two methods that you can use to identify if a particular solution is supported for the VMware Cloud Foundation release you have deployed.
Method One - Viewing Tags on core.vmware.com VMware utilizes a single landing page within the Cloud Platform Tech Zone website known as core.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #2 (Oct 2021)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 26-Oct-2021
Welcome to Edition #2 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing a number of incremental changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.1.0 release Additional Operational Guidance Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support of the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #1</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 05-Oct-2021
Last month we released VMware Validated Solutions for background reading check out my original post here, this fundamental shift in developing VMware Validated Solutions now allows us to deliver incremental value over time, this is just the first of what I hope to be many updates but I'm really excited to share the following announcements with you all today:
General Availability of Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation The Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution, illustrates adapting a dual-instance software-defined data center (SDDC), deployed on top of VMware Cloud Foundation, to provide disaster recovery of the vRealize Automation and vRealize Operations Manager components within the Management Domain as well as lay the foundation to protected customer workloads within the VI Workload Domain.</description></item></channel></rss>