<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCF Installer on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf-installer/</link><description>Recent content in VCF Installer on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2025, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/vcf-installer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VCF Installer: Retrieve Component Passwords from VCF Installer</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-installer-retrieve-passwords/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-installer-retrieve-passwords/</guid><description>
When the auto-generate passwords options is selected within the VCF Installer UI, there maybe a scenario where you need to perform troubleshooting and a need to login to one of the underlying component appliances. Of course this is only possible if you know the passwords that were auto-generated, its relatively simple to retrieve the JSON specification used to perform the implementation from the VCF Installer appliance itself.
The following procedure demonstrates how you can retrieve a specific section of the JSON specification.</description></item><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Installer: Commands for VCF Installer in PowerCLI</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vcfinstaller-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-vcfinstaller-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vcf.Installer, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support VCF Installer Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a VCF Installer Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a VCF Installer instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VcfInstallerServer -Server sfo-ins01.sfo.rainpole.io -User admin@local -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultInstallerConnections.</description></item><item><title>VCF Installer: Streamlining VMware Cloud Foundation Deployments</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-installer-introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-installer-introduction/</guid><description>
What is the VCF Installer Appliance? The VCF Installer is a new unified appliance for VMware Cloud Foundation 9.0 which is a direct replacement for VMware Cloud Builder used in previous versions. Developed and delivered as part of the same OVA as SDDC Manager the bring-up capabilities of VMware Cloud Builder have been ported over.
In addition the Deployment Parameter Workbook has been completely deprecated and replaced with a new VCF Installer User Interface.</description></item></channel></rss>