<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2024, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where Has The VMware Validated Solution Content Gone</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-content-locations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-content-locations/</guid><description>
Since the acquisition of VMware by Broadcom there has been a significant amount of effort behind the scenes to consolidate systems, processes and portals, as a result of this work a couple of key areas have been affected that impact VMware Validated Solutions. If as a result you have been struggling to find the content then read on!
VMware Validated Solutions Landing Page When we first launched VMware Validated Solutions back in October 2021 we decided to utilize one of the Technical Marketing portals known as TechZone and in particular the core.</description></item><item><title>Test</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/html-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/html-test/</guid><description>
&lt;!DOCTYPE HTML> Welcome test html content</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Blog Index</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated 08-Oct-2024 VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. Over time the team intends to add incremental value where opportunities arise and I plan to share as much detail as I can with each new update using my What's New for VMware Validated Solutions series of blog posts. I've decided to create this single landing page where I will provide a consolidated list of links to the relevant Editions of this series so you can bookmark this single page for ease of use.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #26 (October 2024)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-26/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 08-Oct-2024
Welcome to Edition #26 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, this is the update for October 2024, the highlights of which are:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.2.1 to VMware Validated Solutions Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.12.0 Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.2.1 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.2.1 for the following VMware Validated Solutions:
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Private AI Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Ransomware Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Cross Cloud Mobility for VMware Cloud Foundation General Availability of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #25 (July 2024)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-25/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 23-Jul-2024
Welcome to Edition #25 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, this is the update for July 2024, the highlights of which are:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.2.0 to VMware Validated Solutions Enhancements to Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Enhancements to Intelligent Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation New end-to-end automated implementation using PowerShell for all VMware Validated Solutions Support for automated deployment of Solution Interoperability from the validated solution menu Guidance on importing the VMware Aria Suite OVA files into a vSphere Content Library Signed Certificate Generation using the PowerShell Module for VMware Validated Solutions Deprecation of Cloud-Based Workload Protection for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.</description></item><item><title>Simplified Consumption of PowerShell Automation with VMware Validated Solutions</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-powershell-menu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-powershell-menu/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 13-Jun-2024
Background When we started on the VMware Validated Solution journey nearly three years ago, one of the main criteria we agreed on was to provide our customers with an automated way to deploy and configure whatever was defined within a solution. During the process we also did some analysis on tooling and came to the decision that we would use PowerShell as our automation tool of choice based on the flexibility it gave us.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #24 (May 2024)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-24/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-May-2024
Welcome to Edition #24 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, this is the update for May 2024, the highlights of which are:
New Solution – Private AI Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Added Support for VxRail to Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation Added Support for VMware Aria Automation 8.16.2 to Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Added Support for VMware Site Recovery Manager 9.</description></item><item><title>Native PowerCLI Modules for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-powercli-main/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-powercli-main/</guid><description>
The Birth of PowerVCF Back in January 2020 my friend and colleague Brian OConnell embarked on a community project to write a PowerShell module to make consumption of the VMware Cloud Foundation APIs simple and easy to consume by VI Admins, each cmdlet was hand-built using standard PowerShell verbs that the community is well versed in consuming. He saw that the need for automation within our customer based was growing and at the time there was no alternative solution available.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #23 (March 2024)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-23/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 26-Mar-2024
Welcome to Edition #23 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, this is the update for March 2024, the highlights of which are:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.1.1 for all VMware Validated Solutions Update to password management for the latest Photon OS Various enhancements to Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Intelligent Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Cloud-Based Workload Protection for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Cloud-Based Ransomware Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Cross Cloud Mobility for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #22 (January 2024)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-22/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 30-January-2024
Welcome to Edition #22 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, this is a our first update for 2024 and the team has been busy over the festive period. Highlights include:
New Solution – Intelligent Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation Architectural change to Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Multi-instance support for Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Various enhancements to Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Deprecation of VMware Aria SaaS based validated solutions.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #21 (October 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-21/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 07-November-2023
Welcome to Edition #21 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, slightly delayed due to the availability of VMware Cloud Foundation 5.1 but today we announced the following updates:
New Solution – Cloud-Based Ransomware Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Updated branding from VMware vRealize Suite to VMware Aria Suite. Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.1.0 to all VMware Validated Solutions Added support to upgrade VMware Aria Suite Lifecycle to version 18.</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Workload Domains</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-04/</guid><description>
This is the final part of my blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. At this point you should have completed the following tasks:
Downloaded All Bundles Initial Health Check SDDC Manager Upgrade SDDC Manager Configuration Drift Update We are now ready to begin the process of upgrading the individual components within a Workload Domain, for this we must first start with the Management Domain before we can carry out any component upgrades of a VI Workload Domain.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #20 (September 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-20/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 26-September-2023
Welcome to Edition #20 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution – Cross Cloud Mobility for VMware Cloud Foundation Cross Cloud Mobility for VMware Cloud Foundation We are delighted to announce the release of this brand-new VMware Validated Solution.
The Cross Cloud Mobility for VMware Cloud Foundation is a well-architected validated solutions that provides detailed design, implementation, configuration, and operation guidance on establishing business workload mobility and migrating the workloads between a VMware Cloud Foundation instance and a VMware Cloud on AWS SDDC through the use of the VMware HCX service.</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-03/</guid><description>
This is part three of a four part blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. If you have been following the series so far then you will have your bundles downloaded, and performed various health checks to confirm that all is well and will now be ready to start the upgrade process.
Upgrading VMware Cloud Foundation is a multi-stage process, this post will focus on upgrading SDDC Manager which in itself involves two step:</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Perform Health Checks</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-02/</guid><description>
This is part two of a four part blog series in which I talk about automating the VMware Cloud Foundation upgrade process. In part one we discussed downloading the bundles to SDDC Manager to prepare the system for the upgrade process, in this post we discuss performing the upgrade pre-checks.
Ensuring your VMware Cloud Foundation instance is healthy prior to starting an upgrade is critical to a successful upgrade, SDDC Manager itself has a pre-check process which is executed on a per workload domain basis.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #19 (August 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-19/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 29-August-2023
Welcome to Edition #19 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution – Cloud-Based Workload Protection for VMware Cloud Foundation Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.5.2 for all VMware Validated Solutions Enhancements to Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Added password policy management design and operational guidance Added use of VMware Cloud Foundation management pack design and implementation Enhancements to Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation Utilization of VMware Cloud Foundation management pack metrics and dashboards Release of Python Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Health Monitoring in vRealize Operations v2.</description></item><item><title>Automating the Upgrade of VMware Cloud Foundation with APIs/PowerVCF/PowerShell</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 21-Sep-2023
A couple of years ago I wrote a series of blogs ( see here ) which discussed the process of automating the deployment procedures of VMware Cloud Foundation using the Public APIs, in this new series we will take a look at how we can automate the steps involved in upgrading VMware Cloud Foundation from one release to another.
But before we can begin performing any actual upgrade steps we must carry out some prerequisites which include:</description></item><item><title>Automating VCF Upgrade - Download Release Bundles</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-automated-upgrade-01/</guid><description>
In order to upgrade VMware Cloud Foundation you must first download the upgrade bundles, I recently wrote a blog Automating the Download of VCF Bundles for a Release on this topic which I shared a script vcfBundleDownload.ps1 which can be downloaded from GitHub which we will utilize as part of the procedure here. The script takes a JSON as input where we define the bundle IDs for download but as part of this post I will share a way to automate that part too.</description></item><item><title>Cleaning Up VCF-password* Accounts from vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrslcm-vcf-password/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-vrslcm-vcf-password/</guid><description>
If you have had VMware Cloud Foundation and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager deployed within your infrastructure for some time you may have noticed in the vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager Password Locker that there are many passwords called VCF-password-&amp;lt; guid &amp;gt;. This is an internal service account used by vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager to make vCenter Server API calls and is rotated automatically by SDDC Manager.
This duplication of accounts happens due to the fact that there is no way to update the existing record and so SDDC Manager has to create a new account when the rotation process occurs.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager with VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-vrslcm-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-vrslcm-upgrade/</guid><description>
VMware Cloud Foundation has come a long way in recent years, one of the biggest developments introduced a few releases back centred around the relaxation of a strict Bill of Materials (BoM) as it pertained to the vRealize Suite ( see here ), the intent being to enable our customers to update the underlying vRealize Suite components faster to adopt new features.
One of the largest and most complex challenges of any integrated software stack is ensuring that the latest and greatest products and features are available to our customers, this is especially so at VMware as we have a number of business groups who own the underlying products consumed by VMware Cloud Foundation.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #18 (July 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-18/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-July-2023
Welcome to Edition #18 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.0.0 for the remaining VMware Validated Solutions Added guidance for vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager Upgrade to vRealize Suite based VMware Validated Solutions Added enhancements to Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Open-source Projects Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.5.0 Release of VMware.CloudFoundation.Reporting v2.3.0 Release of VMware.</description></item><item><title>Remove vRealize Log Insight Agent from SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-remove-liagent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-remove-liagent/</guid><description>
If you have ever wanted to remove the vRealize Log Insight from VMware Cloud Foundation you may have skipped the step to uninstall the vRealize Log Insight Linux Agent from SDDC Manager, whilst the process is documented in the VMware documentation for vRealize Log Insight under Uninstall the Log Insight Linux Agent RPM package the procedure does not help you establish the version installed so here is a quick blog to tie all the information together.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #17 (June 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-17/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 27-June-2023
Welcome to Edition #17 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.0.0 Open-source Projects Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.4.0 Release of VMware.CloudFoundation.Reporting v2.2.0 Release of VMware.CloudFoundation.CertificateManagement v1.1.0 Release of VMware.CloudFoundation.PasswordManagement v1.2.0 Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.0.0 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 5.0.0 of the following VMware Validated Solutions.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation The remaining VMware Validated Solutions are currently being validated and we hope to declare full support in our July Update.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #16 (May 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-16/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 30-May-2023
Welcome to Edition #16 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Cloud-Based Network Visibility for VMware Cloud Foundation Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.5.1 Added enhancements to Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Added enhancements to Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation Added enhancements to Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates for re-branding from VMware vRealize to VMware Aria for SaaS-enabled Solutions Open-source Projects New Module VMware.</description></item><item><title>Introducing a PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-password-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-password-management/</guid><description>
Background In January 2023 through the VMware Validated Solution programme we released both documentation and PowerShell cmdlets to help with the configuration of password policies across the VMware Cloud Foundation platform, enabling our customers to report and configure the password expiration, password complexity, and account lockout policies at scale.
The positive feedback received to date has blown us away and so last month during one of our planning sessions we discussed the merits for spinning out the cmdlets into their own dedicated open-source PowerShell module, during that discussion it was agreed that this would provide us and our customers the following benefits:</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.3.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-230/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-230/</guid><description>
It's been a while since the last update but I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.3.0 for download from the Microsoft PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF v2.3.0 PowerShell Library Download Additions Added region block identifiers for better developer and contributor experience when navigating the PowerShell module code. Added GitHub Pages Documentation for PowerVCF.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #15 (Apr 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-15/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Apr-2023
Welcome to Edition #15 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Update to Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of the PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management Updated release of PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation APIs Updated release of PowerShell Module for VMware Validated Solutions Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation A minor design decision updated in the Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution:</description></item><item><title>New Fling - VMware Cloud Foundation Configuration File Generator</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-fling-cfg/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-fling-cfg/</guid><description>
This week we released a new VMware Fling, VMware Cloud Foundation Configuration File Generator which is a containerized web application developed to replace the Deployment Parameter Workbook used for performing the VMware Cloud Foundation Bring-up of the Management Domain.
VMware Cloud Builder supports providing either the Deployment Parameter Workbook an Excel workbook which is then converted into JSON format and used by the Bring-up engine or simply providing the JSON file already created.</description></item><item><title>Configure Password Policies for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-config/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-config/</guid><description>
In a recent blog ( see here ) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Start-PasswordPolicyConfig which actually performs the configuration of all password policies across the VMware Cloud Foundation instance.
The Start-PasswordPolicyConfig cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management and provides the ability to automate the configuration of password policies using the provided configuration JSON for the following components:</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #14 (Mar 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-14/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Mar-2023
Welcome to Edition #14 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Health Reporting and Monitoring for VMware Cloud Foundation New Solution - Cloud-Based Intelligent Logging for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.1.0 , our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Delighted to announce the release of two brand new VMware Validated Solutions this month.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #13 (Feb 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-13/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Feb-2023
Welcome to Edition #13 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
Added enhancements to Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Added enhancements to Cloud-Based Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Detailed Design Updates to the following design decisions:
Design Decisions on Identity Management
CBO-IAM-SEC-003 - Assign vRealize Operations Cloud service roles to designated users.</description></item><item><title>Generating Password Policy Reports for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Apr-2023
In a recent blog ( see here ) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager to generate the password policy reports.
The Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management and provides the ability to generate two types of HTML reports:
An HTML report showing the current configuration for password expiration, password complexity and account lockout for each component.</description></item><item><title>Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation Overview</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Apr-2023
Password Policy Configuration may not be that important to some but for security teams it’s critical for ensuring their organization is protected. If you have ever looked deep into this area when it comes to VMware Cloud Foundation and the components involved you will quickly realize that unfortunately VMware today does not make things easy for our customers. We have:
lack of consistency with default values lack of consistency with common parameters lack of consistency with API methods lack of consistency with terminology and language This is why with the January Update to VMware Validated Solutions ( see here ) we have spent a significant amount of time reviewing and rewriting all aspects of our content as it relates to Password Policy Configuration.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #12 (Jan 2023)</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-12/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 31-Jan-2023
Welcome to Edition #12 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we announced the following updates:
New Solution - Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Enhancements to Password Policy Configuration within Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v2.0.0 , our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Cloud-Based Intelligent Operations for VMware Cloud Foundation Delighted to announce the release of this brand new VMware Validated Solution.</description></item></channel></rss>