<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on My Cloudy World</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garyjblake.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #8</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-08/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 31-May-2022
Welcome to Edition #8 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.7.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #7</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-07/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 28-Apr-2022
Welcome to Edition #7 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following updates:
Added support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0 release Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.6.0, our PowerShell module developed to ensure robustness, consistency, and accelerate implementation Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.1.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Additional PowerValidatedSolutions Automation</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #6</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-06/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 29-Mar-2022
Welcome to Edition #6 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional automation based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.5.0 release Additional Operational Guidance (example Personas) Additional automation for procedures within Solution Interoperability section Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Solution Interoperability Design Decision Changes
IAM-WSA-LOG-003 - Configure a dedicated Workspace ONE Access agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN (NEW) IAM-WSA-LOG-004 - Configure a dedicated Photon OS agent group and assign the standalone Workspace ONE Access FQDN.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #5</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-05/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 22-Feb-2022
Welcome to Edition #5 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.4.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0 Delighted to announce support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.4.0.
Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Advanced Load Balancer for VMware Cloud Foundation Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Added a procedure for configuring a Ping adapter for the standalone Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #4</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-04/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Jan-2022
Welcome to Edition #4 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.3.0 release Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support for the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.
Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation Updates Implementation Added PowerValidatedSolutions automation to the following procedures:</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Identity and Access Management Validated Solution</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs/vvs-post-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs/vvs-post-01/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution it’s primary purpose is to provide customers a consistent way of integrating the foundational components of VMware Cloud Foundation (vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager) with an organizations identify provider delivering operational consistency and flexibility.
The Identity and Access Management solution achieves this by connecting components using Active Directory over LDAP/LDAPS and utilizing Active Directory Global Groups to assign individual component level role access and then nested Global Groups to assign a collection of roles based on personas.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</guid><description>
Are you using the PowerValidatedSolutions PowerShell module? Have you found an issue that you want to report? Maybe you have an enhancement idea!
The source code for PowerValidatedSolutions can be found on Git Hub at https://github.com/vmware-samples/power-validated-solutions-for-cloud-foundation, from here you can log issues and enhancements. Fork the branch and provide direct contributions.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</guid><description>
Did you know that the PowerShell module PowerValidatedSolution can be used for more than implementing the VMware Validated Solutions?
Whilst the primary goal for the PowerShell module has been to enable a robust and automated way to implement the various procedures across solutions, its very nature unlocks the power for cmdlet's to be used across the VMware portfolio. One of the fundamental directives for our development work was to minimize the reliance on other PowerShell modules.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library.
PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Added Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet to get the connection status of VI Workload Domains to vRealize Log Insight. Rename Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #3</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-03/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 30-Nov-2021
Welcome to Edition #3 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing the following changes:
General Availability of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0 Release of PowerValidatedSolutions v1.2.0, which is a PowerShell module that we have developed to not only accelerate the implementation of Validated Solutions, but ensure consistency and robustness. Here's a list of what's changed (this and previous updates can be tracked by reading the CHANGELOG.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-05/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution places certain configuration requirements on VMware Cloud Foundation, this detailed is documented within the Before You Apply This Guidance section of the Solution Guide.
To locate the Before You Apply This Guidance use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Click on the top page of the docs.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item><item><title>VMware Validated Solutions - Tips Index</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 10-Nov-2021
VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. To help customers get the most out of VMware Validated Solutions I've put together a number of short tips, bookmark this page for easy access.
Remember to check back from time to time!
Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported Identify What’s Required from a VMware Cloud Foundation Perspective Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Architecture Supported</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-04/</guid><description>
Each VMware Validated Solution is validated against a specific architecture configuration of VMware Cloud Foundation, to confirm and identify if your configuration is supported you use the Design Objectives table.
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.vmware.com.
Click View Resource Page for the Validated Solution your interested in.
Click Read More under the Design Objectives tile.
Review the VMware Cloud Foundation architecture support and Workload domain type support rows to confirm support.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Last Time Content Was Updated</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-02/</guid><description>
When updates are made to VMware Validated Solutions the changes could affect a section of the guide or the whole guide, each page within the guide itself has an Updated on value at the top of the page.
In addition its possible to identify where content has changed from individual Validated Solution resource page on core.vmware.com, each tile which provides a link to a particular section of the content has a date too, this is updated each time changes are made within that section.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Review Detailed Update History for a Validated Solution</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-03/</guid><description>
As each VMware Validated Solution is updated its important that you as the customer are able to obtain a precise and accurate account of what has changed within the guide, Validated Solutions do this through the use of an Update History table that is published within the About section of the document.
To locate the Update History use the following process:
Connect to the VMware Validated Solutions landing page on core.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Quickly Identify the Version of VMware Cloud Foundation Supported</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-01/</guid><description>
VMware Validated Solutions have been developed so that they can support multiple versions of VMware Cloud Foundation, this means they only need to be updated when absolutely necessary which is typically driven by significant architecture changes.
There are two methods that you can use to identify if a particular solution is supported for the VMware Cloud Foundation release you have deployed.
Method One - Viewing Tags on core.vmware.com VMware utilizes a single landing page within the Cloud Platform Tech Zone website known as core.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Blog Index</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/whats-new-index/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 22-Feb-2022
VMware Validated Solutions are byte sized solutions developed to extend the foundational capabilities of VMware Cloud Foundation, for background reading see my previous post here. Over time the team intends to add incremental value where opportunities arise and I plan to share as much detail as I can with each new update using my What's New for VMware Validated Solutions series of blog posts. I've decided to create this single landing page where I will provide a consolidated list of links to the relevant Editions of this series so you can bookmark this single page for ease of use.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #2</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-02/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 26-Oct-2021
Welcome to Edition #2 of the What's New for VMware Validated Solutions, today we are announcing a number of incremental changes:
Additional support for Dell VxRail Additional automation across solutions based on the PowerValidatedSolutions v1.1.0 release Additional Operational Guidance Added Support for VMware Cloud Foundation 4.3.0 / 4.3.1 on VxRail Delighted to announce support of the following Validated Solutions running on Dell VxRail based systems in addition to vSAN Ready Nodes.</description></item><item><title>What's New for VMware Validated Solutions - Edition #1</title><link>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garyjblake.github.io/post/vvs-whats-new/edition-01/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 05-Oct-2021
Last month we released VMware Validated Solutions for background reading check out my original post here, this fundamental shift in developing VMware Validated Solutions now allows us to deliver incremental value over time, this is just the first of what I hope to be many updates but I'm really excited to share the following announcements with you all today:
General Availability of Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation The Site Protection and Disaster Recovery for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution, illustrates adapting a dual-instance software-defined data center (SDDC), deployed on top of VMware Cloud Foundation, to provide disaster recovery of the vRealize Automation and vRealize Operations Manager components within the Management Domain as well as lay the foundation to protected customer workloads within the VI Workload Domain.</description></item></channel></rss>