<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/api/</link><description>Recent content in API on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2025, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Password Policies for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-config/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-config/</guid><description>
In a recent blog ( see here ) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Start-PasswordPolicyConfig which actually performs the configuration of all password policies across the VMware Cloud Foundation instance.
The Start-PasswordPolicyConfig cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management and provides the ability to automate the configuration of password policies using the provided configuration JSON for the following components:</description></item><item><title>Generating Password Policy Reports for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Apr-2023
In a recent blog ( see here ) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager to generate the password policy reports.
The Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Cloud Foundation Password Management and provides the ability to generate two types of HTML reports:
An HTML report showing the current configuration for password expiration, password complexity and account lockout for each component.</description></item><item><title>Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation Overview</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</guid><description>
Last Updated: 25-Apr-2023
Password Policy Configuration may not be that important to some but for security teams it’s critical for ensuring their organization is protected. If you have ever looked deep into this area when it comes to VMware Cloud Foundation and the components involved you will quickly realize that unfortunately VMware today does not make things easy for our customers. We have:
lack of consistency with default values lack of consistency with common parameters lack of consistency with API methods lack of consistency with terminology and language This is why with the January Update to VMware Validated Solutions ( see here ) we have spent a significant amount of time reviewing and rewriting all aspects of our content as it relates to Password Policy Configuration.</description></item></channel></rss>