<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware Cloud Foundation on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/vmware-cloud-foundation/</link><description>Recent content in VMware Cloud Foundation on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/vmware-cloud-foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library.
PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Added Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet to get the connection status of VI Workload Domains to vRealize Log Insight. Rename Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item></channel></rss>