<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerVCF on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/powervcf/</link><description>Recent content in PowerVCF on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/powervcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generating Password Policy Reports for VMware Cloud Foundation</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy-reports/</guid><description>
In a recent blog (see here) I provided an overview of Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation, in this blog we will take a deep dive on using Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager to generate the password policy reports.
The Invoke-PasswordPolicyManager cmdlet is part of the PowerShell Module for VMware Validated Solutions and provides the ability to generate two types of HTML reports:
An HTML report showing the current configuration for password expiration, password complexity and account lockout for each component.</description></item><item><title>Password Policy Configuration for VMware Cloud Foundation Overview</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-password-policy/</guid><description>
Password Policy Configuration may not be that important to some but for security teams it’s critical for ensuring their organization is protected. If you have ever looked deep into this area when it comes to VMware Cloud Foundation and the components involved you will quickly realize that unfortunately VMware today does not make things easy for our customers. We have:
lack of consistency with default values lack of consistency with common parameters lack of consistency with API methods lack of consistency with terminology and language This is why with the January Update to VMware Validated Solutions (see here) we have spent a significant amount of time reviewing and rewriting all aspects of our content as it relates to Password Policy Configuration.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Private Cloud Automation Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-pca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-pca/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Private Cloud Automation for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to implement a modern cloud automation platform that delivers self-service automation, DevOps for infrastructure, and orchestration.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Automation and the integration with one of more VMware Cloud Foundation instances.
The roles and personas documented (here) should be considered as a minimum requirement when implementing the Private Cloud Automation validated solution but there is nothing stopping customers adding more granular roles where possible or even personas that better align with their own organizations roles and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Operations Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iom/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Operations Management for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide operations monitoring, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Operations and the configuration of it's management packs to collect data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.
The roles and personas documented (here) should be considered as a minimum requirement when implementing the Intelligent Operations Management validated solution but there is nothing stopping customers adding more granular roles where possible or even personas that better align with their own organizations roles and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Intelligent Logging and Analytics Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-ila/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Intelligent Logging and Analytics for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide logging, analytics and reporting for VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure components.
This is achieved through the deployment of vRealize Log Insight and the configuration of it's content packs to collect log data from ESXi, vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center, SDDC Manager, vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager, and Workspace ONE Access.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Developer Ready Infrastructure Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-dri/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Developer Ready Infrastructure for VMware Cloud Foundation validated solution it’s primary purpose is to provide enterprise grade infrastructure, suitable for developers to consume for the deployment of modern applications, using VMware Cloud Foundation as its foundational layer.
The Developer Ready Infrastructure validated solution achieves this by walking you through the configuration of each of the required components including NSX-T Data Center, vSphere Storage Policies, vSphere Tanzu and more.</description></item><item><title>Automating the Download of VCF Bundles for a Release</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-bundle-download/</guid><description>
If you have been through the process of performing an upgrade of VMware Cloud Foundation you will know the process involves downloading a number of bundles. VMware Cloud Foundation includes the following types of bundles.
Install Bundles, An install bundle includes software binaries to install VI workload domains and vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager. Update or Upgrade Bundle, An update or upgrade bundle includes software binaries to update the appropriate VMware Cloud Foundation software components.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-220/</guid><description>
It's been a while since the last update but I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.2.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF v2.2.0 PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed Get-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet when passing the ID of the Application Virtual Network the response was failing. Enhancements Updated Get-VCFFederation cmdlet to check the system version, multi-instance management is deprecated in VMware Cloud Foundation v4.</description></item><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Identity and Access Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-end-to-end-iam/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution it’s primary purpose is to provide customers a consistent way of integrating the foundational components of VMware Cloud Foundation (vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager) with an organizations identify provider delivering operational consistency and flexibility.
The Identity and Access Management solution achieves this by connecting components using Active Directory over LDAP/LDAPS and utilizing Active Directory Global Groups to assign individual component level role access and then nested Global Groups to assign a collection of roles based on personas.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</guid><description>
Are you using the PowerValidatedSolutions PowerShell module? Have you found an issue that you want to report? Maybe you have an enhancement idea!
The source code for PowerValidatedSolutions can be found on Git Hub at https://github.com/vmware-samples/power-validated-solutions-for-cloud-foundation, from here you can log issues and enhancements. Fork the branch and provide direct contributions.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</guid><description>
Did you know that the PowerShell module PowerValidatedSolution can be used for more than implementing the VMware Validated Solutions?
Whilst the primary goal for the PowerShell module has been to enable a robust and automated way to implement the various procedures across solutions, its very nature unlocks the power for cmdlet's to be used across the VMware portfolio. One of the fundamental directives for our development work was to minimize the reliance on other PowerShell modules.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-217/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixes Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Enhancements Renamed Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet. Renamed Set-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvROPs to align with new Get-VCFvROPSConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-cb-backup/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.3 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-213/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.3 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Enhancements Updated ResponseException cmdlet to improve the error handling message output. Additions Added Add-VCFApplicationVirtualNetwork cmdlet to create the Application Virtual Networks. If you would like to learn more about VMware Cloud Foundation or PowerVCF, check out these links:</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.2 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-212/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.2 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
This latest release is a very minor update containing a few bug fixes as well as adding support for the new VIEWER Role added in VMware Cloud Foundation 4.2 within the New-VCFGroup cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.1 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-211/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.1 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.
Categorycmdlet NameDescriptionCommentUsers and GroupsGet-VCFCredentialRetrieves a list of credentials.UPDATE: Added support for the vRealize credentialsBundlesStart-VCFBundleUploadStarts upload of bundle to SDDC ManagerUPDATE: Allows the import of a bundle based on offline download.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-210./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.1.0 Here's a run down of what's new in this release:
Rename of a few existing cmdlets to align with approved verbsEnhancements to execution response messagesRemoval of the use of Write-Host The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.0.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-200./</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.0.0 for download from the PowerShell Library. PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
What's New in PowerVCF v2.0&amp;lt; Along with a number of new or modified cmdlets the following enhancements have been made:
Grouped cmdlets based on order of API documentationEnhancements to reuse duplicate codeUpdated for consistency in the use of codeSupport for the new token-based authentication model The following table provides a detailed breakdown of all the cmdlet changes for this release.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v1.2.0 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-ga-120/</guid><description>
If you follow my posts you will know that in January I posted about the release of PowerVCF which is a PowerShell based CLI that exposes the public APIs of VMware Cloud Foundation to be easily consumed by VI Admins (see Introducing PowerVCF – Power to VI Admins).
As mentioned before PowerVCF is a open source project and the team has been working hard in their spare time to continue to evolve the cmdlets it offers.</description></item><item><title>Introducing PowerVCF - Power to VI Admins</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-intro/</guid><description>
Back in December I was chatting with my good friend and colleague Brian O'Connell about automating a bunch of post configuration tasks within VMware Cloud Foundation using the new Public APIs, and it was during that conversation he shared a pet project he had been working on called PowerVCF, the idea behind PowerVCF being a way to allow VI Admin's to easily consume the new public APIs we began shipping with VMware Cloud Foundation much in the same way PowerNSX and PowerVRA come about.</description></item></channel></rss>