<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerVCF on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/powervcf/</link><description>Recent content in PowerVCF on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2022, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/tags/powervcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>End-to-End Automation of Identity and Access Management Validated Solution</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-post-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs/vvs-post-01/</guid><description>
If your not already familiar with the Identity and Access Management for VMware Cloud Foundation Validated Solution it’s primary purpose is to provide customers a consistent way of integrating the foundational components of VMware Cloud Foundation (vCenter Server, NSX-T Data Center and SDDC Manager) with an organizations identify provider delivering operational consistency and flexibility.
The Identity and Access Management solution achieves this by connecting components using Active Directory over LDAP/LDAPS and utilizing Active Directory Global Groups to assign individual component level role access and then nested Global Groups to assign a collection of roles based on personas.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Contributing to PowerValidatedSolutions Source Code</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-07/</guid><description>
Are you using the PowerValidatedSolutions PowerShell module? Have you found an issue that you want to report? Maybe you have an enhancement idea!
The source code for PowerValidatedSolutions can be found on Git Hub at https://github.com/vmware-samples/power-validated-solutions-for-cloud-foundation, from here you can log issues and enhancements. Fork the branch and provide direct contributions.</description></item><item><title>VVS-Tip - Unlocking Automation Capabilities with PowerValidatedSolutions</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vvs-tips/vvs-tip-06/</guid><description>
Did you know that the PowerShell module PowerValidatedSolution can be used for more than implementing the VMware Validated Solutions?
Whilst the primary goal for the PowerShell module has been to enable a robust and automated way to implement the various procedures across solutions, its very nature unlocks the power for cmdlet's to be used across the VMware portfolio. One of the fundamental directives for our development work was to minimize the reliance on other PowerShell modules.</description></item><item><title>PowerVCF v2.1.7 - General Availability</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/powervcf/powervcf-post-10/</guid><description>
I'm pleased to announce the general availability of PowerVCF v2.1.7 for download from the PowerShell Library.
PowerVCF is a open source project and the team works on adding support when time permits.
Download It Here: PowerVCF PowerShell Library Download
Fixed New-VCFClustercmdlet where incorrect braces prevented the ability to retrieve response information. Added Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet to get the connection status of VI Workload Domains to vRealize Log Insight. Rename Set-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet from Set-VCFvRLI to align with new Get-VCFvRLIConnection cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>Configure VMware Cloud Builder as a Backup Target for SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-post-01/</guid><description>
By default when VMware Cloud Foundation is deployed, SDDC Manager and NSX-T Data Center are configured to use an SFTP service running locally on the SDDC Manager Appliance. For production environments its critical that this is changed before going live to ensure that you have the ability to recover in the event of a disaster.
The requirements of using an SFTP in my experience seem to fall through the gaps during most initial deployments and as a result it takes organizations some time to get all the requirements put in place.</description></item></channel></rss>