<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SDDC Manager on My Cloudy World</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/sddc-manager/</link><description>Recent content in SDDC Manager on My Cloudy World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2019–2025, Gary Blake; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/categories/sddc-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using VMware.Sdk.Vcf.SddcManager: Commands for SDDC Manager in PowerCLI</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sddcm-cmdlets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf-90/vcf-90-powercli-sddcm-cmdlets/</guid><description>
VCF PowerCLI 9.0 now includes a module called VMware.Sdk.Vcf.SddcManager, this modules contains auto-generated cmdlets to support SDDC Manager Public APIs. Use can use this post as a quick reference guide.
Connecting to a SDDC Manager Instance with Local Credentials Start a PowerShell session.
Connect to a SDDC Manager instance using local credentials by running the following command:
1Connect-VcfSddcManagerServer -Server sfo-vcf01.sfo.rainpole.io -User administrator@vsphere.local -Password VMw@re1!VMw@re1! Once connected the following information is stored in $defaultSddcManagerConnections.</description></item><item><title>Viewing Service Details Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-view-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-view-services/</guid><description>
In this procedure, we will use the /v1/vcf-services API to retrieve service details for a SDDC Manager instance.
SDDC Manager APIs Used
POST /v1/tokens GET /v1/vcf-services Obtaining Service Details for all Services from SDDC Manager Procedure
Connect to the SDDC Manager appliance over SSH. Replace the values in the sample code with values for your SDDC Manager instance and run the commands SSH session. 1sddcManagerFqdn=$&amp;#39;sfo-vcf01.sfo.rainpole.io&amp;#39; 2sddcManagerUser=$&amp;#39;admin@local&amp;#39; 3sddcManagerPass=$&amp;#39;VMw@re1!VMw@re1!&amp;#39; Authenticate to SDDC Manager and obtain a token by running the following command: 1TOKEN=$(curl -k -X POST https://$sddcManagerFqdn/v1/tokens -H &amp;#39;Content-Type:application/json&amp;#39; -d &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#39;$sddcManagerUser&amp;#39;&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#39;$sddcManagerPass&amp;#39;&amp;#34;}&amp;#39; | jq -r &amp;#39;.</description></item><item><title>Viewing Network Pool Details Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-view-network-pools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-view-network-pools/</guid><description>
In this post we will use curl to view the details of a Network Pool in SDDC Manager.
SDDC Manager APIs Used
POST /v1/tokens GET /v1/network-pools View All Network Pools Configured in SDDC Manager In this procedure we will authenticate to SDDC Manager and then using the /v1/network-pools API we will retrieve a list of all the Network Pools configured within the SDDC Manager instance.
Procedure
Connect to the SDDC Manager appliance over SSH.</description></item><item><title>Obtaining a Token Using Curl with SDDC Manager</title><link>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-authentication/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://jadenetworksolutions.co.uk/post/vcf/vcf-curl-sddcm-authentication/</guid><description>
Interacting with the Public APIs for SDDC Manager can be achieved in many ways, my normal goto is PowerCLI but that requires the installation of the required modules and of course PowerShell itself to be available on either the component your wanting to interact with or a remote management host. If your looking for a faster method for interacting with the Public APIs then CURL is your new best friend.</description></item></channel></rss>